Ò×¿¼·¶ÎÄÁù
In the above picture, a man drives his car to buy some soy sauce,
but evidently the errand takes him too long a time.
Amusing as the picture seems,
it compels us to consider this question: is private car a plus or a minus?
It has been a controversial issue whether or not we should possess a car.
Advocates say we derive numerous benefits from private cars,
which enable us to go anywhere at any time without relying on public transport.
But others hold views to the contrary.
They argue that traffic jams caused by the booming number of private cars
are driving people mad. In addition, the exhaust fumes emitted by motor vehicles,
most of which are private cars,
remains one of the primary sources of pollution in cities.
It seems unwise to abandon private vehicles in light of its convenience.
However, at least we can take actions to reduce its disadvantages.
Above all, we need to limit the use of private cars.
Private car owners in Beijing, for example,
are allowed to drive only on alternate days.
In addition,
it is essential to improve public transport and encourage the use of bicycles.
As is clearly shown in the above picture,
rather than drive a car, the man may just as well ride a bicycle,
which will save him much valuable time in traffic congestion.